Charles Uhlinger Papers 5228
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Charles Uhlinger Papers
1912-1955
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Uhlinger, Charles
5228
3 cubic feet
3 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Papers on the maritime industry collected by Mr. Uhlinger in preparing his doctor's thesis, The Wages of American Seamen 1934-1952.
5556492
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 06, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 21, 2017
Biographical / Historical
Charles W. Uhlinger received his B.A. from Hofstra College in 1941 and a B.S. from the United States Merchant Marine Academy in 19^. He received his M.A. from Columbia University in 1948 and in 1956 he was awarded the Ph. D. from Fordham University.
This collection consists of papers on the maritime industry collected by Mr. Uhlinger in preparing his doctor's thesis, The Wages of American Seamen 1939- 1952. Mr. Uhlinger was well qualified to write in this area as he had served aboard merchant vessels both as a seaman and as an officer. Mr. Uhlinger had also
served on the faculty of the New York State University Maritime College.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of papers on the maritime industry collected by Mr. Uhlinger in preparing his doctor's thesis, The Wages of American Seamen 1934- 1952.
The collection is organized along the lines of Mr. Uhlinger's thesis as far as possible. The School has a copy of the thesis on microfilm which is shelved with the cataloged microfilm, No. 229.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Arrangement
Series Section 1
Sub-Series Part 1 Sub-Series Part 2
Series Section 2
Sub-Series Part 1 Sub-Series Part 2 Sub-Series Part 3 Sub-Series Part 4 Sub-Series Part 5 Sub-Series Part 6
Series Section 3
Transport workers -- United States; Wages -- Transport workers -- United States; Transport workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Collective labor agreements -- Transport workers -- United States; Collective bargaining. Merchant marine. United States.; Merchant marine. Industrial relations. United States.; Merchant marine. United States. Manning of vessels.; Strikes and lockouts. Shipping. Pacific Coast (North America); Wages. Shipbuilding industry. United States.; Axtell, Silas Blake, 1885-; Curran, Joseph Edwin, d 1906-1981; Uhlinger, Charles; Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.). Maritime Committee.; International Seamen's Union of America; National Maritime Union of America; Pacific Maritime Association; San Francisco Bay Ports Commissions; United States. Bureau of Labor Statistics.; United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on Labor and Public Welfare.; United States. Dept. of Commerce.; United States. Division of Ship Statistics; United States. Maritime Administration.; United States. Maritime Commission.; United States. Maritime Commission. Post-War Planning Committee.; United States. War Shipping Panel.; United States. Office of Subsidy and Government Aid.; United States. President's Advisory Committee on the Merchant Marine.
5556492
- Series Section 1
  - Sub-Series Part 1
    - Marine Labor History (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bibliography: Transportation (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bibliography: Water Transportation (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Coastwise and Intercoastal Shipping: Economic Importance of (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Coastwise and Intercoastal Shipping: Economic Survey of (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Coastwise and Intercoastal Shipping: San Francisco Bay Ports Area (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Glossary of Shipping Terms (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Great Lakes Shipping: St. Lawrence Seaway (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Great Lakes Shipping: Survey of (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Job Descriptions (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Manning: Normal Manning Practices (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Manning: Ships and Manning Scales (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Manpower Requirements and Labor Supply (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Merchant Marine: Attainable National Objectives for, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Merchant Marine: Economic Survey of, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Merchant Marine: History and Function Policies, Practices, & Problems, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Merchant Marine: Postwar Outlook, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Merchant Marine: Problems & Policies, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Merchant Marine: Report of Presidents Advisory Committee, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Merchant Marine: Restoration of American Shipping, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Merchant Marine: Size, Composition, and Quality Survey, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Merchant Marine: Military Jurisdiction over Merchant Seamen (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Overseas Trade, Participation of American Ships:, 1912-1951 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Seamen: Andrew Furuseth (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Seamen: Training and Education (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Tanker Fleet: U.S. Tanker Fleet Survey, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Tanker Fleet: World Tanker Fleet Review, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Tramp Shipping, Its Value, Need and Cost (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Working Conditions, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Working Conditions: River Towboats, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Working Conditions: Shipyards, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Sub-Series Part 2
    - Federal Transportation Program, Issues Involved (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Government Aid: Foreign and U.S. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Government Aid: Present Shipping Policy (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Government Subsidies: Congressional Hearings, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Government Subsidies: Analysis of Construction and Operating Subsidies, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Government Subsidies: Effects of Devaluation of Foreign Money (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Government Subsidies: Financial Data (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Government Subsidies: Maritime Subsidy Policy, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Government Subsidies (Box 1, Folder 40)
      Scope and Contents
      Need for 1951
    - Government Subsidies: Operating Differential Contracts, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Interterritorial Freight Rates, 1943 Reports (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Marine Legislation, Bills to Amend (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Maritime Industry, Tax Deferment and Tax Exemption Benefits (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Merchant Fleet Protection, Tanker Fleet (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Merchant Marine Act of 1936, Proposals to Amend (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Merchant Marine Development & Regulation in the U.S. History (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Parity Principle (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Rules & Regulations: Cargo and Miscellaneous Vessels (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Rules & Regulations: Tank Vessels (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - U.S. Maritime Commission (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Series Section 2
  - Sub-Series Part 1
    - Arbitration: National War Labor Board (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Arbitration: Private (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Arbitration: U.S. Department of Labor (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Arbitration: War Shipping Panel (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Collective Agreement: NMU (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Collective Agreement: Dispute (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Collective Agreements (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Collective Bargaining: On Government Operated Vessels (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Collective Bargaining: During World War II (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Collective Bargaining: Session (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Collective Bargaining: Table of Maritime Agreements (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Labor-Management Relations: East Coast Oil Tanker Industry (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Labor-Management Relations: Subsidization of Seamen's Wages (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Labor-Management Relations: West Coast Maritime Industry (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Strikes & Work Stoppages, West Coast Maritime Industry (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Wage Increases, Graphs (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Sub-Series Part 2
    - Monthly Wage Rates, 1932-1952 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Monthly Wage Rates: Base Wage Tables (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Monthly Wage Rates: East Coast Dry Cargo (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Monthly Wage Rates: Hillcome Steamship Company (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Sub-Series Part 3
    - Overtime Earnings: On U.S. Flag Merchant Ships (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Overtime Earnings: Overtime and Penalty Earnings (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Overtime Earnings: Under Pacific Coast Contracts (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Overtime Rates (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Working Schedules, Stewards Department (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Sub-Series Part 4
    - Comparative Analysis: Earnings and Conditions of Work (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Comparative Analysis: Seamen's Wages Relative to the Standard of Living of Their Respective Nations (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Comparative Wage Data (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Foreign - U.S. Wage Comparison (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Foreign Wages and Earnings (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Railway Wage and Earning Data (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Seamen's Earnings: General (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Seamen's Earnings: Average Monthly, Deep Sea (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Seamen's Earnings: Guaranteed Annual Wages (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Seamen's Earnings: Longshore (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Seamen's Earnings: Tanker Fleet (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Seamen's Earnings: Under Pacific Coast Contracts (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Sub-Series Part 5
    - Exclusive Compensation Act, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Pension Plans, Negotiated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Pension and Welfare Plans, Combined (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Safety (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Unemployment Insurance (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Vacation Plans, Negotiated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Welfare Plans: Student Reports (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Welfare Plans: Negotiated (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Workmen's Compensation and the Protection of Seamen (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Sub-Series Part 6
    - Feeding Costs (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Fixed and Variable Costs (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Labor Costs: General (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Labor Costs: Longshore (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Labor Costs: Overtime Work Items (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Labor Costs: Under Pacific Coast Contracts (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Operating Costs (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Regulations Prescribing Method of Determining Profit (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Series Section 3
  - Bibliography on index cards (Box 3, Folder 30)